WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Get that, will you?
Anna, what have you got for hair
in the evening?
Er, diamond stars and one tiara.
We may not use it,
but I'd rather be safe than sorry.
Wrap it all in brown paper so they
won't have a basket to worry about
at the other end.
Suitcases are finished.
OK. I'll go up and get them now.
It's quite a palaver, isn't it?
Do they go to Duneagle every year?
Not last year,
after Lady Sybil died.
And not during the war.
But otherwise, it's the high spot
of His Lordship's calendar.
Come on - quickly, quickly.
Straight on to the wagonette.
Why aren't we taking the guns?
Because you're going stalking,
Mr Molesley,
and stalking
does not involve shotguns.
Maybe we should take them,
just to be sure.
I'm already sure.
Yeah.
Why don't I go on my own?
Darling, this isn't 1850.
No-one expects me to hide indoors
until the baby's born.
Well, all right. If you're certain.
If you change your mind at any point
and want to come home, just tell me.
Well, no.
We'd be thrilled to see you.
It just seems an awfully long way
to come for a walk.
Who was it?
My editor, Michael Gregson.
He's realised he'll be in Scotland
at the same time as us.
Don't tell me
he'll be near Duneagle. Apparently.
What a coincidence.
Yes, isn't it?
Ask him over. We want to meet him,
don't we, Robert?
Why are the Flintshires based
in Scotland when the title's Welsh?
Shrimpie's grandmother was Countess
of Newtonmoor in her own right.
It's now their courtesy title.
Dare one ask
why he's called Shrimpie?
It was a nursery game.
Louisa was a lobster, Agatha was
a shark, which is easy to believe,
and I suppose
Shrimpie was a shrimp.
Is he very small?
No, but he was the youngest.
I'm sorry you won't be with us.
Why should they ask me?
I don't know them at all.
Nor do I, really.
Are you sure you should be going?
Don't be a spoilsport.
I still have a month.
(HARRUMPHS)
You don't want me to go, either?
I think you should take good care
of yourself, milady. That's all.
I agree. Right, let's get started.
I told Mama we'd be on the platform
at quarter to, and we're late.
(STEAM HISSES)
Feels like a holiday, doesn't it?
Oh, don't worry. It won't feel
like a holiday once we get there.
Let me just retrieve the briefcase.
They might need it for the journey.
(LAUGHS)
I want to check their dining-car
seats for lunch.
Do you like Scotland?
Have you really never been?
They didn't go last year.
And you know I wasn't
a proper lady's maid before that.
No, I meant as a child,
or when you were growing up.
My mother's mother was Scottish.
She was a Keith -
did I tell you that?
No.
Now, you won't forget to take her
for some decent walks?
She can be lazy.
Don't worry. She'll be fine.
Have you got everything?
Well, if I haven't,
it's too late now.
Do you think it's wise
to leave him here unsupervised?
What do you mean? Well, I know
he's house-broken, more or less,
but I don't want freedom
to go to his head.
I'll keep an eye on him.
He can come to dinner tonight.
Oh.
Well, that's one day taken care of.
Only nine to go!
(STEAM HISSES)
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
So will we have a bit of a break
while they're away, Mr Carson?
What?
He meant can we expect
some time off?
For an outing, or something.
I don't understand.
Has someone forgotten
to pay your wages?
No.
Exactly.
Now, we will start
with the ceremonial wear,
and when that's done, I want all the
silver brought down for cleaning -
one room at a time.
(THEY SNIGGER)
And don't you maids
think you're out of it.
We'll give every room a thorough
cleaning while they're away.
You can let them have
a bit of free time, can't you?
If they get the extra work done,
then I'll think about it.
Edna?
Why hasn't Mr Branson been asked
to go with the others?
I'm sure I don't know.
I wonder what Lady Flintshire
made of her cousin's daughter
eloping with a chauffeur.
It's not your place to wonder.
What was she like?
She was a sweet, kind person.
And a real beauty.
Inside and out.
You'd think
she could have done better.
But SHE didn't think she could do
better, and that's what matters.
He's nice-looking -
I'll give him that.
I don't think you're required
to give him anything.
She'll be a long way off.
But not in the middle of nowhere.
There are hospitals in Inverness.
You mean I'm being an old woman.
Well, after Sybil,
who can blame you?
It'll be very quiet for you,
with them all gone.
It will.
Why not come to supper tomorrow?
I daren't call it dinner, as I
don't know what we can conjure up.
But do come.
I don't want to be a nuisance.
You won't be.
Tom Branson's here this evening,
so I shall be back in training.
Thank you. I'd be delighted.
Oh, Mr Carson sent me up to clear.
He thought you'd be out of here.
I should be.
Seems sad for you to be left behind
all on your own.
I'm used to it.
Yes. Yes, of course. You would be.
It must be very hard.
Don't worry about me.
Plenty to do.
You're the new maid, aren't you?
What's your name?
Edna.
Edna Braithwaite.
Hello!
Robert, how are you?
Shrimpie, this is so nice of you.
Nonsense. I can't tell you
how glad we are.
Cora. Edith.
Hello!
Daddy, this is Matthew,
defender of the downtrodden -
including me!
I don't know why I've earned that.
We met at your wedding. Mary.
Aunt Violet, we feel so privileged
to have lured you this far north.
You flatter me,
which is just as it should be.
We've got lots planned.
There's the Ghillies' Ball,
which Mary's always the star of.
Rose, don't wear them out.
We remembered how you liked
our mountain loch,
and we've arranged for luncheon
to be taken up there one day.
That was my idea.
Well, whosever idea it was,
it's a lovely one.
Tea is in the library
when you're ready to come down.
(EXCITED CHATTER)
I'm looking for a Mrs Patmore.
Why is that, then?
I've got some deliveries for her.
Really? Where from?
You're not very curious,
are you (?)
And you're not one of our regulars.
Well, if you must know, I've taken
over from Mr Cox in Thirsk.
Mr Patmore sent an order in to him.
What's this?
Do I hear my name taken in vain?
I was just explaining.
You sent an order in to Mr Cox.
I've bought the shop
and all the stock,
so I took the liberty
of filling it out.
How do you know
she wants to do business with you?
All right, Mr Barrow. I can fight
my own battles, thank you.
So where is this order, then?
Bring it to the kitchen.
And what's your name,
since you know mine?
It's Tufton. Joss Tufton.
Hmm.
What's this?
Some vichyssoise left over
from last night.
Oh, that's heaven!
Any more leftovers going begging?
Have a bit of the tart if you like.
I don't mind if I do.
I've not had food that good since
the last time I were in London.
I'm not just a pretty face.
This family's fallen on its feet
and no mistake.
I wouldn't mind eating food like
that every day.
Enough of the flannel. I'll keep
the order, but if there's owt amiss
you'll be hearing from me.
Let's just hope that there's
something not quite up to scratch.
Why do you say that?
Cos I'd like to hear
from you again, Mrs Patmore.
I would.
Be off with you, you cheeky devil!
Go on!
Are you not hungry?
It's a bit early for us. We eat
our dinner after the family's.
Oh, I agree with you, Miss Crawley.
In London we eat last thing,
when all the work is done,
and I prefer it.
How about you, Miss Grantham?
Me?
Oh, I do what I'm told.
It makes me laugh when I hear
Miss O'Brien and Mr Bates
called Mr and Miss Grantham.
Miss Bates and I don't often work
in the same house party.
Of course - you two are married,
Miss Crawley.
How do you manage at home,
being called Bates and Bates?
We're not. They still call me Anna,
like when I was a housemaid.
Which isn't right.
I do so hate
to see a lady's maid downgraded.
Oh, I so agree, Miss Grantham.
But then, we would think alike,
wouldn't we?
It's a treat to have a kindred
spirit come to stay. It really is.
Tell Mrs Crane I've gone up.
I'll announce dinner in 10 minutes.
How marvellous.
I should remind you
that he'll be back
to pipe us awake at eight o'clock.
And he keeps it up
through breakfast.
So the chances of getting back
to sleep again are nil.
All right, Shrimpie,
the point has been made.
You've no need to apologise.
I'm glad to see
the old ways being maintained.
Tomorrow, we'll kit you out
with some rifles for some practice.
And what is planned for the women?
Well, there's a picnic by the loch
the day after tomorrow.
And the Ghillies' Ball on Friday
is always good fun.
As long as it's not too much fun.
As a matter of fact, a friend
of mine is staying quite nearby.
I thought I might telephone him.
But you must ask him here.
She doesn't have to.
Oh, please do.
I'd like to meet him.
That's settled, then.
Invite him to dinner tomorrow night.
Unless, of course, Susan objects.
Why on earth would I object?
I thought it was
too good to be true.
He's sent dried ginger
instead of fresh.
It's my fault. I just put 'ginger'
because Mr Cox knew what I liked.
I might go into Thirsk tomorrow.
I can take it back for you
if you want.
Would you? You should go with him,
Alfred. You'd like that shop.
Who's doing what tomorrow?
Mr Barrow's going in to Thirsk.
I said Alfred should go with him.
Who says I can spare them?
What about Mr Branson's luncheon?
I doubt he needs an under-butler,
Mr Carson.
Or two footmen.
He told me he'd get lunch
at the Grantham Arms.
So can they go?
I suppose so. But there's a lot
to be done, and don't forget it.
I hope you'll come here
whenever you like.
It must be odd, being alone
in that great house.
Well, I'm not alone.
There's people I know well.
Except they're all downstairs,
and I'm up.
Well, why not take the opportunity
to spend some time with them?
I don't think old Lady Grantham
would approve of that.
No, but I doubt she approves of
the working class learning to read.
Tom, can I take this chance to say
you've managed a very delicate
transition superbly?
Thank you.
But don't be too eager to please.
You have a new identity.
And I don't mean because
you're not a chauffeur any more.
You are the agent of this estate,
and as the agent,
you have a perfect right
to talk to anyone
who works under you.
Anyone you choose.
That's quite a speech.
I mean it.
You have a position now,
and you're entitled to use it.
Mr Branson!
I didn't want to drag one of you
upstairs to open the door.
That was kind.
I wondered if you would allow
the maids to clean during the day
while the family's in Scotland?
You don't need my permission.
But I do.
And if you want to use a particular
room, then please let me know
and we'll vacate it at once.
Thank you, Mrs Hughes.
Good night.
Good night, Mr Branson.
I was a bit shaken up on the train.
Please don't say anything -
I don't want to worry Mr Crawley.
You don't want to give him
the satisfaction, you mean.
I can't spoil his last treat
before fatherhood claims him.
Not that he'll change his ways
much, if he's like most men.
Are they looking after you?
Oh, yes.
But I'm a bit nervous
about this Ghillies' Ball.
Why?
I suppose I just feel so...
..English.
I don't want to look a fool.
I love reeling. If I weren't
pregnant, I'd dance until dawn.
But you ARE pregnant, milady.
(BAGPIPER STRIKES UP)
Bloody hell!
Welcome to the Highlands.
Now take your time.
You're not chasing a pheasant.
Be calm and confident.
I thought I was.
These are noble beasts.
We must take them out
for the good of the herd,
but they've earned our respect
and deserve a clean death.
Fine words.
How are you getting on?
Not too bad, Your Lordship.
That's high praise from Nield.
He's being kind.
I doubt your father
needs much practice.
His Lordship was born with a rod
in one hand and a gun in the other.
That sounds rather uncomfortable.
I love to hear your ghillie speak.
It's like a voice from
a bygone age.
Where's Susan? Aunt Violet
wanted to see the gardens,
so I left them to it.
Rose is not anxious
for her mother's company.
How's it going with you?
I'm in for an adventure.
I'm to don a ceremonial uniform
and hold mighty sway
on some distant shore.
You won't mind a foreign posting?
Why not?
They say a change of sink
is as good as a rest.
Hello!
You do know where it will be?
No, but it will be filthy and
dirty, and the food will be awful
and there will be no-one to talk to
for a hundred square miles.
It sounds like a week
with my mother-in-law.
Will Rose go too?
Why?
What's she been saying?
My dear, no-one can accuse me
of being modern,
but even I can see
it's no crime to be young.
I know that, Aunt Violet.
But you don't see
how they gang up on me.
Then I shall strive
to keep the peace.
That's all very well,
but you are my mother's sister,
and you can jolly well
be on my side.
I'd like to travel more.
We see a bit of London in the
season, otherwise it's Yorkshire.
What about the House of Lords?
When His Lordship goes up,
he just takes Mr Bates with him
and stays in his club,
which is no use to me.
We're headed
for an outpost of empire.
Her Ladyship's dreading it,
and so am I.
Oh, I don't know.
Something different -
I could quite fancy that.
Well, not me.
All sweat and gyppy tummy? Oh, no.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Did you get him?
I did.
He said he'd love to come.
I'm sure he would.
What do you mean by that?
I can't imagine Mr Gregson finds
himself at Duneagle Castle often.
Or anywhere like it.
Mary, that sounds very snobbish.
What's he doing up here?
He's on a sketching holiday.
He's sketching and fishing.
Fishing? Oh, well,
that's something, I suppose.
What do you suppose?
For some reason, Mary's decided
to be nasty about Michael Gregson.
I was questioning his motives
for being in the Highlands.
He's brought his pencils and his
rods. What's wrong with that?
Nothing at all, so there.
Afternoon, George.
Can you do me a sandwich, please?
This is very daring -
sitting in a pub on your own.
Want the village
to cut you off dead forever?
I knew you were coming in,
and I don't care
about all that stuff.
Do you have the day off?
I'll fudge it, but no. We've extra
cleaning while the family's away.
Of course, YOUR family.
Well, I am and I'm not,
as I'm sure you know.
Anna said when you first came back
as Lady Sybil's husband,
you refused to dress the part,
but you do now.
I was tired
of talking about my clothes
every time I came downstairs.
I'm still the same man inside.
Then why not join us for dinner
one night, instead of eating alone?
Well, tell her
I'll not forget again.
By heck, it were worth a visit,
Mr Tufton. What a range!
I've never heard
of some of those spices.
I'll tell you what. We've got
a fair starting here on Friday.
I run a stall,
and so do some of the suppliers.
Why not come?
What sort of fair?
Well, the usual sort of fair.
Food, games, Morris dancers...
Can we get the time off?
I don't see why not. Jimmy?
Well, I might come if there's
a crowd of us, but not otherwise.
Have you got a minute?
I'll just put a note in that bag
for Mrs Patmore.
Go on, then.
I can't let them go gallivanting off
to every fair at the drop of a hat.
I mean, what are we paying them for?
They've been working very hard.
Don't they deserve a treat?
Excuse me.
On Friday,
can I take the afternoon off?
I'll make the servants' dinner
and Ivy and Daisy can serve it.
Mrs Patmore doesn't often
take the time she's allowed.
What about Mr Branson?
I'll see to Mr Branson.
Where are you going,
or shouldn't we ask?
There's a fair in Thirsk.
A friend of mine has asked me
to meet him there.
I don't believe it.
Must I be undermined at every turn?
Ooh!
What's got into him?
Mr Barrow and the boys
have asked to go to the same fair,
and he was trying to find a way
to say no.
Why don't we all go?
I'll make Mr Branson a tray and
he can keep charge of the house.
He won't mind. Come on.
It'll be fun.
(MURMUR OF VOICES)
Mr Gregson!
This is very kind of you,
Lady Flintshire. Not a bit.
It's a pleasure to welcome a friend
of dear Edith's.
What a disappointment.
He looks perfectly normal.
Since he came with the express
purpose of dining at Duneagle,
he obviously bought a set of tails.
Come and meet my parents.
Mama, Granny, Papa,
this is Mr Gregson.
Lady Grantham.
You know, I started to read your
magazine because of Edith's column,
but now I wouldn't miss it.
It puzzles me why you choose to
employ amateurs like my daughter.
I agree. Well, is the distinction
very meaningful?
Surely the most important thing is
whether she has something to say?
Come and meet my sister Mary.
Do stand up.
You're slouching like a field hand.
Might I just have five minutes
without being criticised?
We knew things were awkward
between them.
But now that I'm here, I don't think
Susan handles it very well.
It is so complicated with a young
daughter who's full of new ideas.
She thinks you're fighting her,
when all the time,
you're just frightened.
I'm sorry.
We all miss her.
Every single day.
We're going in, everyone.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Come in.
Who's that?
Would you like me to take Miss
Sibby up to the nursery? Thank you.
Go with Edna, darling.
Come here.
Can I ask you something?
Be my guest. Please.
Are you ashamed of who you are,
or of who you were?
Is that why you won't
eat your dinner with us?
No.
It is not.
Well, I'd better be going.
It never really gets dark here,
does it?
Not like further south, no.
Let's take a picnic out tomorrow.
Just the two of us.
They'll be gone for the day.
What do you say?
I'd love it.
(SOBS)
Is everything all right, milady?
It will be, if you don't tell
my mother you saw me smoking.
Don't worry - you're safe with us.
Would you like a peppermint?
I better had. Thank you.
Oh, sorry.
It's just my mother has been
unusually impossible this evening.
My whole childhood would seem
impossible to you, milady,
but I survived - so will you.
Rose, who are you talking to?
Shh.
Come inside at once.
Everyone's in the drawing-room.
Thanks for the mint.
I should be away.
Oh, don't go just yet.
Heaven knows I've no desire to.
It makes a welcome change
from reading a medical journal
and going to bed with,
well, a glass of whisky.
Goodness - I wondered what you
were going to say for a moment!
I sometimes forget, when we meet
in the splendour of the abbey,
that you were a doctor's wife.
That you know what my life consists
of in a way that no-one else does.
At any rate, not around here.
I know.
It's a relief to be able to talk
without having to explain oneself,
isn't it?
A relief, and a privilege.
And I hope we can do it again.
Soon.
Matthew's asked me to go out
stalking with him tomorrow.
So I thought I would.
Michael, can I ask you
why you're here?
Tell me the truth. Please.
Well, I want to get
to know your family.
What do you hope to achieve?
I thought if they knew me,
if they came to like me,
they might find it easier
to be on my side.
It won't change the basic facts,
though, will it?
Edith, my basic fact is
that I'm in love with you.
You know that already.
Do I?
Yes, I suppose I do.
I want you in my life.
And I want to be in yours.
That's all very well, but...
..I just can't see a happy ending.
Edith, dear.
Stop fascinating that young man and
come and make a four at bridge.
(SIGHS)
I've asked Gregson to come.
I won't see you all day,
so he'll be company.
He was right to invest
in those tails, wasn't he?
You know Susan's invited him
to the Ghillies' Ball?
He probably had reeling classes
before he left London.
Don't dislike him
before you know him.
That's the hallmark of our parents'
generation, and I forbid it.
Just be as nice as you are.
You think me nice,
but nobody else does.
What makes you so sure I am?
Because I've seen you naked,
and held you in my arms.
And I know the real you.
Goodness, what a testimonial.
Oh, go on. You were young once.
I'm young now.
Well, not old.
All the more reason to say yes.
Oh, you'll enjoy yourself.
No. I won't be coming.
If I came, they wouldn't have fun.
They'd spend the day
looking over their shoulder.
Well, I'm going,
whether I spoil their fun or not.
That's different.
They respect you, of course,
but I am their leader.
Well, that's put me in my place.
Don't envy me, Mrs Hughes.
You know what they say.
'Uneasy lies the head
that wears the crown.'
The wind is north-west
and getting stronger.
We should get started.
Well, good hunting, everyone.
Oh, Shrimpie's not stalking.
He's coming with me.
Mr Crawley? Mr Gregson?
Is your picnic under control?
Of course.
I'm worried about Mary
bumping through the glen.
She doesn't have to come.
No, I know.
But she will. We'd best get going,
or we're in for some stick.
Walk on.
I'm not sure I'm going tomorrow.
It's such a waste of money.
Oh, come on. You've enough for
a few rides and a beef sandwich.
I can buy you all a bottle of pop.
What an offer! Let's take him up
on it, before he thinks again.
Thank you, Mr Barrow,
but I can buy my own pop.
Don't pretend you've money to burn.
I can always get money.
The store cupboard's open
if you need anything.
No, but I do have something
to ask you.
Now, where did I put that box?
This one?
Did you see the lid?
Mrs Kearney's dress shop in Ripon.
She's got a fancy man,
I'm telling you.
Mrs Patmore?
Why not? She's a woman, isn't she?
Only technically.
(BIRDSONG)
Oh. I was looking for Lady Mary
to tell her we're going.
She's already gone down, milady.
You were kind to cheer me up,
yesterday.
I did feel terribly blue.
That's all right.
You must let me know
if I can return the favour.
As a matter of fact...
..there is something
you could help me with.
(Shall I take it from here?)
We can bring it to a better place.
We don't rush things at Duneagle.
Well, that's true, God knows!
You don't think it's too girlish?
What's the matter with
being girlish, once in a while?
Heaven knows
we don't have much opportunity.
Well, I'd wear a coat over it,
so it wouldn't jump out at you.
I hope he's worth it.
Read that.
'I hope you will allow me
the honour of squiring you
through the day.'
No man's wanted to 'squire' me
since the Golden Jubilee.
Even then, he expected me
to buy the drinks.
Suppose he wants something more.
I beg your pardon?
There is only one reason a man
his age courts a respectable woman.
He finds himself in need of a wife.
(FLOWING WATER)
Is there anything to drink?
There certainly is.
Beer!
That's very racy of you.
I am racy.
What shall we drink to?
The future.
And your Scottish blood.
What are you up to?
Nothing.
Nothing!
(GIGGLES)
Well, you managed that very well.
When the time comes for me to go,
I'll ask them to send for you.
Is everything all right, Shrimpie?
Of course. Impertinent to ask.
No, it's not all right.
But what's the point
in talking about it
when there's nothing to be done?
I'm not so sure.
The Marlboroughs have got a divorce
and you still see them around.
But Sunny Marlborough
has no official post.
He hasn't been in office
since the war.
While you must have Susan
next to you under the tropical sun.
She'll do it well.
She can teach diplomacy to experts.
But?
We don't like each other.
How can I help, Mr Branson?
I was thinking...
It's just...
Yes?
I thought I'd come down
for supper tonight.
Catch up with your news.
If you would like to, of course
you'd be very welcome.
We don't eat late
while the family's away,
so dinner will be
at about eight o'clock.
I'll see you then.
Fains I tell Mr Carson.
How tiny the glens make one feel.
That is the thing about nature.
There's so much of it.
Must be lovely to be queen
of such a kingdom.
You're right.
We're very lucky in this.
Goodness - we weren't expecting
male company for our feasting.
I'm sorry to disappoint you.
How did you get on?
Very well. Not too long a trail,
and death by a single shot
at the end of it.
Nield is cock-a-hoop.
Well done, Papa.
Your reward will be
to join the ladies' lunch.
An added bonus.
I hope it's venison.
Quite right.
We ought to eat what we kill.
Stop talking nonsense and tell
McCree to lay two more places.
10 hours crawling through heather
and nothing to show for it.
Perhaps it's a parable of life.
Reminds me of the trenches rather.
Hours of inching through mud
with no discernible purpose.
(RUMBLE OF THUNDER)
Why don't you come fly-fishing
tomorrow?
We might see a bit more activity.
You could bring your evening clothes
to change at Duneagle.
That's rather an imposition.
That's what you're here for,
isn't it?
To get to know us all.
And you didn't bring your tails all
this way to dine in a country pub.
No.
No, I suppose not.
(PEAL OF THUNDER)
Have you got a minute?
Because, if you haven't,
it's perfectly fine.
A minute for what?
Her Ladyship would like a word.
What does she want with me?
Well, what do you think?
She wants to make a fuss,
like she always does.
(RUMBLE OF THUNDER)
This is so kind of you...
O'Brien, milady.
..O'Brien. It's just that Wilkins
here isn't quite able to understand
what I'm getting at when I'm
describing Lady Grantham's hair.
I understand, milady, it's just -
Could you help her?
You'll know exactly what I mean.
Oh, er...
Well, it's a question of body,
milady.
You need more volume to begin,
before you sculpt it, so to speak.
I knew you'd have the answer.
If I could...
Oh, please, please, please.
Wilkins, pay close attention
to what she's doing.
Yes, Your Ladyship.
Bombay? That sounds rather modest
for a marquis.
Well, no, not if it's a step
towards the Viceroy's crown.
I don't know about that. All I do
know is it's going to be very hot.
And all the costumes
of imperial rule
are always so peculiarly unsuited
to the climate.
Will you take Rose?
I don't think we should,
but Susan won't discuss it.
Unless you want her married
to a third-rate colonial official
with no money and bad teeth,
Susan had better think again.
Just as he stood,
a gust of wind comes into the corrie
from behind us,
a hind got our scent,
and they were away.
Really, darling. It's boring enough
to hear about when you succeed...
What did you think of Michael?
He seems like a nice chap.
We're going fishing tomorrow.
He's had such a lot to put up with.
Oh, God. Not one of your
hard-luck cases, is he?
Why must you sound so heartless?
Actually, I think India
would be fascinating,
but I know that Mummy and I
would drive each other mad.
You mustn't be too hard
on your mother.
You know, it's natural for her
to be concerned.
Concerned?
Is that what she is?
I'm sure she loves you very much.
What's this?
Rose was just saying
how nice your hair looks tonight.
He's what?
It's only meant to be friendly.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Good evening, Mr Carson.
I don't expect you to approve.
Well, now. Come along in.
I hope you won't show an example
of rudeness to the younger staff.
I was hoping to catch you.
What about a glass of something?
No, I won't stay,
but I've had an idea.
I saw Mrs Hughes
in the village today,
and she told me the servants have
got up a party for the Thirsk fair.
And, erm, I was wondering
if you'd like to go.
What, with the servants?
No, of course not.
But I could drive us over
for an hour or two.
I'm told they do it well.
Why not?
It might be fun.
Good. I'll come for you at five.
Know what you're going to wear?
Nothing good, that's for sure.
I'll keep an eye on the place.
Oh, don't say you're not coming.
I-I thought you could drive us.
There is no need for impertinence,
Edna, thank you.
You're all right.
I'm happy to drive them.
But who'll stay here?
I will.
You don't want to come to the fair?
I would sooner chew broken glass.
It was lovely, milady.
But what about you?
Did you enjoy your day?
Oh, I was stupid
to go to the picnic.
We were shaken about in that trap
like dice in a cup.
Stay in bed for the morning.
And take it easy at the ball.
Are you looking forward to it?
I am rather. I've been planning
a bit of a surprise for Mr Bates.
Why? What sort of surprise?
No. It's a surprise for you, too.
Don't forget what I said.
What was that?
Just that I've promised
to rest tomorrow.
Which is annoying, because
I'd rather come out with you
and interrogate Mr Gregson.
Is he going to propose?
I think so. But he's quite opaque.
A man of mystery.
Edith could use some of that.
You are horrid when you want to be.
I know, but you love me, don't you?
Madly.
(HUMS)
And the man on your right.
And...
And then round,
in a figure of eight.
(HUMS)
(BOTH LAUGH)
You take it easy
with Mr Barrow today.
I don't mean...crawl all over him,
but don't spoil things.
You're a fine one to talk.
Who rang the police
in the first place?
Sod this. I'm bushed.
Suppose someone comes in?
They'll find a man
sitting in an armchair.
They'll survive it.
(SNIGGERS)
Funny thing with Mr Barrow is,
he won't hear a bad word about you.
Why? What have I done?
I only meant he won't let anyone
speak against you.
What on earth is going on in here?
We were just - You were just taking
advantage of the cat's absence.
We'll see what
Mr Carson has to say.
Mrs Hughes.
Mr Branson.
What time are we leaving?
About half past four.
But Mr Stark can easily drive us.
Because I'm so high and mighty?
You're part of the family now.
There's nothing false in that.
I know.
I hope you do.
Because if someone is trying
to make you feel awkward,
they're in the wrong, not you.
I'll be there at half past four.
(WALTZ PLAYS)
I said I'd meet him at his stall.
What's that?
He asked me to bring sandwiches.
Can I come? I want to find out
where the best food stalls are.
Why don't we all go?
Here's something for us.
Alfred? Mr Branson?
Let's give it a go.
I don't mind.
What about you?
Isn't it a bit rough for Mr Barrow?
Oh, I think I could manage.
I'll come and cheer you on,
if that's all right.
Wait till Mrs Hughes sees that!
Come on.
Don't care about any tug-of-war.
Let's go and find some games.
You do know they're all fixed?
I don't think they are.
They must have seen you coming.
Come on, ladies -
drink up, drink up.
We can go and join in the fun then.
What about your stall?
Lucy can look after the stall,
can't you, Lucy?
Cheeky!
I hope you don't mind my saying so,
Mrs Patmore,
but in that blouse, you look as if
you've just stepped out of Vogue.
I don't mind.
I don't believe you, but I don't
mind you saying it at all.
You're generous with compliments.
I love to be in love, Mrs Hughes,
I'll not deny it.
Any time, any place -
I love to be in love!
Get away, you daft beggar!
I must find Alfred and tell him
where to look for the spice stall.
If you don't mind my leaving you?
No, I don't mind that, either.
Oh, yes!
(CHEERING)
Any side bets before we begin?
Who'd bet on them?
What odds would you give us?
10 to one.
Right. A quid on the Downton team.
(LAUGHS)
Any more?
That's enough money down the drain.
Ready?
One moment.
Mr Tufton,
you'll join our team, won't you?
As a Downton supplier?
If you want us, lad, aye.
Had you already seen him?
What do you think?
Will you be so kind?
Tufton's at your service.
Good afternoon, ladies.
They needed a bit of muscle,
so they sent for Tufton. Feel that.
Eh?
Very strong.
That's my name - Joss Tufton.
See that stall with the spices on?
That's me.
If you want a bit of spice in
your life, send for Tufton.
Take the strain!
Pull!
(SHOUTS OF ENCOURAGEMENT)
Of course it's a lot to ask,
but what else can I do?
I'm prevented
from divorcing a woman who...
..doesn't even know who I am.
Does the law expect me
to have no life at all until I die?
Would Lord Grantham?
My father-in-law
would be the first to understand
you have to make some sort of
life for yourself beyond the pale.
I do. You can't expect him to want
you to involve his own daughter.
Not when all you have to offer
is a job as your mistress.
No. I love her.
I...
I'm offering my love.
You've been misled
by our surroundings.
We're not in a novel by
Walter Scott.
(CHEERING)
Come on, lads! Come on, boys!
Come on, Mr Branson!
Mr Tufton!
Pull it! Pull the rope!
Come on, boys!
(CHEERING)
I declare the Downton team
the winner!
Thank you very much.
Well done, Jimmy.
Thank you, Mr Branson.
So the laws of society should
be preserved, no matter what?
Edith gave me the impression
you were a freer soul than that.
I find that hard to believe.
I agree your position is tragic
and I'm very sorry.
You can't imagine I would let Edith
slide into a life of scandal
without lifting a finger
to stop her?
Will you tell Lord Grantham?
I'm not going to tell anyone, but
you must see it's quite hopeless.
You're saying I should leave now?
Not stay for the ball?
No.
Use it to say a proper goodbye.
You owe her that.
Oh, don't!
Oh! Sorry!
(GIGGLES)
Let's have a drink.
One all round, all right?
My pleasure, lads, my pleasure.
Hoop yourselves a fortune, ladies.
Thruppence for three.
Thruppence? Never in this world.
Look at the prizes, eh?
Not fairground rubbish here,
you know.
When did you last see
a gold sovereign?
When did you last win one?
What's the matter?
I want a go, but Daisy
thinks it's too expensive.
Oh, have it on me.
Here. One go for each of them.
Are you drunk?
'Thank you, Jimmy.
How kind of you.'
It is kind. Thanks very much.
Don't flash your money about.
It's my money.
I'll do what I want with it.
Remember, the ring must go
over the base and lie flat.
Ohhh. Now you.
I don't believe it!
I've never won nothing before!
Don't let it make a gambler of you.
See? I told you they were honest.
(Didn't I say to make the blocks
too wide for the bally rings?)
Thanks for not telling Mr Carson
about us sitting down
in the drawing-room.
We'd not be here now.
Well, don't let me catch you again.
Oh, there's Mrs Crawley
with Dr Clarkson!
This is where I belong. I know it.
What, at a fairground stall?
No, working with food. Cooking.
Preparing.
Don't sound so tragic.
Your time at Downton
won't be wasted.
You know how a great house runs
now. That'll come in handy -
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Well, that was great fun!
With the music and everything.
I'm glad we came.
I'm very glad you came.
Shall we sit down for a bit?
Let me fetch you a drink.
There's something I want to ask you.
Punch?
That would be lovely.
You won't miss service?
Well, I've not been unhappy,
you know. I can't pretend I have.
But taking orders from a husband,
it's got to be better than
from some jumped-up lord or lady.
It's still orders, isn't it?
Did you make this pate, as well?
All with my own fair hand.
Well, fair hand or red flipper,
you're the cook for me.
(FAIRGROUND MUSIC IN DISTANCE)
Where do you think you're going,
my laddo? Get out of my way.
Take him.
Let him go.
And who's gonna make me?
I am.
Leave it, Jimmy!
Run! Run!
Go!
There.
Thank you.
I'm so sorry.
The queue was a mile long.
What was it you wanted to ask me?
Ah.
Well, I'm not sure I have the right.
If you'd like me
to come back to the hospital, I -
No, it's not the hospital.
I'd be interested to know...
..if you've ever thought
of marrying again.
Are you thinking of
getting married, Dr Clarkson?
Because if you are, you're a better
man than I am, Gunga Din.
Why?
Well, with good friends like you,
I enjoy my life as it is,
and I wouldn't want to risk things
by changing it.
Excuse me!
Doctor! Doctor,
you've got to come now!
What is it?
It's Thomas. Please!
Rose, you are not wearing
that dress, and that is final.
Oh! Daddy, please stick up for me.
She looks like a slut.
Heavens! That's not a word
you often hear among the heather.
But Princess Mary has one
just like it. It's the fashion now.
Then it is a mad fashion.
Aunt Violet, tell her.
Oh, my dear, in my time, I wore
the crinoline, the bustle
and the leg-o-mutton sleeve.
I'm not in a strong position
to criticise.
Rose, take Aunt Violet
through to the ballroom.
Now.
Do you know, Rose dear, the first
Ghillies' ball I ever attended
was at Balmoral in 1860.
Yes, I'd not long been married,
and I confess, you know,
I was a little alarmed,
because all the men
were as tight as ticks. (GIGGLES)
Don't blame me
if she is the object of ridicule.
I won't, whatever else
I might blame you for.
You are a fool to indulge her.
Have you never stopped to think -
Will you stop?!
Stop making everyone so unhappy
all the bloody time!
Forgive me.
I think I know where I'm going.
I'll come with you.
Is there any chance of apprehending
these men? Not really.
But why did you get into a fight?
It's not like you.
What have they taken? Every penny
I had, but it wasn't much.
Is anything broken?
I don't think so.
He'll be all right?
We ought to get him home.
I'll fetch the wagonette.
I'll help him.
(GROANS)
Lean on me.
Well done. Up here.
(HUMS)
(BABY CRIES)
(CRYING INTENSIFIES)
Hello? What's the matter
with you, eh?
Where's your na... Ohhh!
Let's have a little chat about it.
Eh? There.
(LIVELY MUSIC
ON FIDDLES AND ACCORDION)
We must all join in.
Not me, milady,
and I have a cast-iron alibi.
I can do an eightsome and a dashing
white sergeant, but that's it.
I'm very good. Hamilton House is my
favourite, but I know most of them.
You won't be doing any tonight.
Spoilsport!
I think Mr Crawley's right, milady.
Will you be staying out of it?
We'll have to see.
O'Brien!
Wilkins has been trying her best
to imitate you. What do you think?
It looks very nice, Your Ladyship.
Yes, well, it's not right yet,
but we're trying our best,
aren't we, Wilkins?
I might go and find a drink.
I'll fetch you one.
There's no need. I'll go.
No. I insist.
You're the guest.
You must be careful.
Matthew says it's rather strong.
I should jolly well hope so.
Rose's evening had a bumpy start.
I'm afraid Susan isn't herself.
But she's absolutely herself.
That's the problem.
Oh, dear, poor souls.
It's bad enough parenting a child
when you like each other.
Can I trouble you for a drop
of whisky, Mr Nield?
Certainly, Miss Wilkins.
But I am surprised if it's for you.
Oh, no!
For a guest from the south.
(APPLAUSE AS DANCE ENDS)
(DOOR OPENS)
Oh, you're back, then?
We are.
And we've a few stories to tell.
But you've spent your day
more productively, I see.
Where's Nanny?
I'm not sure,
but she'll find us in a moment.
I was thinking about Lady Sybil
when she was this age.
All we can do for her now
is to cherish her bairn.
And it's lovely
to watch you doing just that.
There's no need to get sentimental,
Mrs Hughes.
Right. Let's get this one
back to bed.
Come on.
Shall we go and look for Nanny?
Where is Shrimpie?
Hiding and licking his wounds.
I'll go in search of him,
poor fellow,
if he hasn't come back.
That's very kind. Thank you.
Don't you want it?
No.
I wouldn't drink that
if I were you, Mr -
Oh, that slipped down a treat!
I'll see if I can get another one.
Each to his own.
Was it always this bad?
Not at the beginning.
We weren't madly in love,
but there was a job to be done,
and we both believed in it.
(SIGHS)
Then the children came along,
and for years
we hardly had time to think.
What went wrong?
First James left,
then Annabel got married.
We started to learn
just how little we have in common.
Why is Susan so hard on Rose?
Who knows?
Perhaps Rose reminds her
of me as I used to be.
Me, when I had
something to live for.
Oh, you have a great deal
to live for.
Duneagle!
I can't remember being as envious
as I have been these past few days.
Don't be. It'll all have to go.
What?
It's my own fault.
If I'd had any gumption
and modernised, as you did...
But I sat on my hands
as the money drained away.
Now it's all gone.
What will you do?
Go to India first, and then London.
Oh, it'll be all right.
What with the club and the Lords,
Susan and I needn't see
too much of each other.
Shrimpie, my dear chap.
I'm so sorry.
Question is: Rose.
What are we going to do about Rose?
(LIVELY MUSIC)
Anna! Come on. This is it.
This is what?
You'll see! Quick! Come on!
Look at Anna.
She never said she could reel!
Bates, did you know?
No, milady. I never knew.
But isn't she marvellous?
Yes.
She is marvellous.
Oh, Mrs Patmore. How kind of you.
I want a word, so I thought we
could have some tea while I get it.
You were right.
He says he loves me
and he can't live without me.
(POURS TEA)
Oh, dear.
What do you mean, 'Oh, dear'?
It's a long time since anyone
wanted to share my seat on the bus,
never mind my heart and home.
I don't know how to say it.
Well, find a way.
Well, I first noticed it when
I was standing at the stall.
He was flirting with
that young assistant
and stroking her...
well, bottom.
What?
It's true.
Then I saw him making eyes
at some other women
when he was pulling
in the tug-of-war.
While I was cheering him?
Later, when I was with Alfred,
I saw Mr Tufton in the crowd,
and he seemed to be chewing
the mouth off some poor woman.
Where was I all this time?
I don't know.
Dreaming of a better life?
Oh, Mrs Patmore, I am sorry.
I don't know
if he wanted to eat a few dinners
before he told you the truth,
or if he planned to marry you
and chain you to the stove.
Either way,
it was the cooking he was after...
..and not me.
I feel terrible.
I should have pulled you away
then and there,
but you were having
such a good time.
Is there anything I can do?
No.
God, I've never felt more relieved
in all my life!
What?
The more he said about how he liked
his beef roasted, his eggs fried
and his pancakes flipped, the more
I wondered how to get away.
And what if he comes back?
He'll get a thick ear,
and no mistake.
But how could he do such a thing,
Mrs Hughes?
How could he lead a poor woman on
like that?
(SIGHS)
You heard him, Mrs Patmore.
Any time, any place -
he loves to be in love.
(BOTH GIGGLE)
And that was really his reaction?
How disappointing.
Well, I wasn't going to tell you
till I was leaving.
Why not?
Because I... I...
I wanted us to have
a last evening together.
This is not our last evening.
Isn't it?
It's odd.
If you'd asked me before tonight,
how I felt about you,
I'm not sure
what I would have answered.
But now I'm absolutely sure,
and this is not our last evening.
(BAND STRIKES UP)
Ha-ha!
(WHOOPS)
What in God's name...
(LAUGHS HYSTERICALLY)
Are you proud of your handiwork?
I don't know what you mean.
Never mind, Miss Wilkins.
It might do him good
to let it all go for once.
And I'm grateful. I am.
What for?
Because I need never be held back
by any sense of loyalty to you.
(MOLESLEY LAUGHS HYSTERICALLY)
They do say there's a wild man
inside all of us.
If only he would stay inside.
I thought you'd like to know
Mr Barrow is feeling much better.
Thank you, but you should go now.
Just wanted to tell you
what a lovely day I've had.
Really lovely.
Do you want to meet for lunch
tomorrow in the Grantham Arms?
Are you all right?
(DANCE ENDS)
I don't think I should have done
that, but I couldn't resist.
This is just what I was afraid of.
Calm down. Everything's fine.
But I wonder, would you mind
terribly if I went home tomorrow?
Of course not.
I'll tell Shrimpie tonight.
No, not you. You must stay here.
What? I don't want to let you
out of my sight.
If you come, Mama and Papa will
leave, and the party will break up.
So what? I'm coming with you.
It's unfair on Susan and Shrimpie.
I'm perfectly all right.
It's only a couple more days.
Let me go,
and I'll see you when I see you.
Please.
Besides, Molesley may need a bit
of time before he's fit to travel.
(SNORES)
That was Mr Bates on the telephone.
Lady Mary and Anna
are coming back today.
They're already on the train.
Well, we'd better look sharp. Edna,
air the room and make up the bed
while I go and talk to Mrs Patmore.
Must I?
Why?
Do you have other plans, Edna?
I said I'd meet...Tom Branson
for lunch in the village.
Did you, indeed?
'Tom' Branson?
Before you start,
it may not be his fault.
Whether it's his fault or not,
she has to go.
Oh, yes.
Of course she has to go.
Will you tell him, or will I?
You'd better do it. I'd only be rude,
which wouldn't help anyone.
You've heard about Mary?
I have. Her maid left a message
with O'Brien.
I hope you don't think her rude.
I know you haven't always
approved of Mary.
She's having a baby.
We all need a little leeway
when it comes to our babies.
And as for the other business,
I'm not as harsh as I was.
Rose is proving quite an education.
I can imagine.
I find myself worrying about Rose
before I even open my eyes
for the morning.
Do you think I'm being stupid?
Not at all. I understand better
than anyone else here could.
Shrimpie wants her to live
at Downton while we're in India.
I've told Robert I would never
agree to that against your wishes.
I know. Thank you.
It's not often that I get support
in this house.
But I wonder now if he isn't right,
and that we need a rest
from one another.
Apart from anything else,
I can't bring her out from Bombay.
But would you be prepared
for all that?
If you want me to be,
and only if you want it.
What about you and Shrimpie?
Oh, we'll soldier on.
Our sort never accept defeat.
Even if I wish we could.
Will you speak well of me to her?
Not every day, but sometimes?
Course I will. I promise.
So I spoiled things for her.
I'm afraid the work
would no longer satisfy her.
I've seen it before.
She'd unsettle the other maids.
I didn't encourage her, you know.
Maybe. But if I may say it,
you didn't discourage her, either.
Can I ask one thing?
That you give her
a decent reference, please.
I will. Though I don't think
she's cut out to be a housemaid.
Would you allow me to speak
as I would have in the old days?
Go on, then.
You let Edna make you ashamed
of your new life.
But you've done well.
And Lady Sybil would be so proud.
I can't bear to be without her.
(SOBS)
You must bear it.
And one day I hope,
and so would she,
you'll find someone
to bear it with you.
But until then, be your own master
and call your own tune.
Thank you.
Milady? Is something the matter?
I don't want to alarm anyone,
but will you leave the cases
and take me
straight to the hospital?
Milady.
What?
Let Mrs Crawley know, and get a
message to Mr Crawley straight away.
Mr Crawley?
(SIGHS) Mr Crawley!
What in God's name...?
Right. All change. The whole family
is coming back tomorrow
and we must be ready to receive them.
Is it because Lady Mary's
in the hospital? It is.
Does that mean she's in danger?
No. It doesn't mean any such thing.
Lady Mary will be perfectly fine,
but we have to make allowances.
Now, do you have everything?
What have I done wrong?
I'm as good as Mr Branson.
And there was nothing improper.
Nothing at all.
I'm sure.
But there are rules
to this way of life, Edna.
And if you're not prepared
to live by them,
then it's not the right life
for you.
It's organised. We've got tickets
for the first train in the morning.
There isn't one before then.
I just wish I was there with her.
I can't wait to get home.
Aren't you enjoying your Victorian
idyll any longer?
I'm glad I was jealous of Shrimpie.
It's made me realise
what a fool I've been.
Downton will survive
because of Matthew's vision.
I'm so pleased to hear you say it.
You always knew
how lucky we are in Matthew,
and now I give thanks for him
as I give thanks
for my home and my family.
And most of all,
I give thanks for my wife.
Send us the news
as soon as you know it.
And thank you for taking in Rose.
We'll make firm plans
when we know when we're leaving.
I'm glad to have her,
now I know it's what you both want.
What I want is for her to know that
family can be a loving thing.
We'll do our best.
Love is like riding,
or speaking French.
If you don't learn it young,
it's hard to get
the trick of it later.
Well said, Shrimpie. And good luck.
What did you tell Mary
about Michael Gregson?
Nothing.
I hope you made it clear
what has to happen.
Oh, yes. We both know
what happens next.
I'll see you at Downton very soon
and thank you both so much.
We look forward to it.
Are we all ready, Bates?
We are, my lord.
(ENGINE STARTS UP)
Mr Carson? I'm going down
to the hospital,
and I think I have what she needs.
If there's anything else at all,
just telephone.
According to the doctor,
there's nothing to worry about.
Of course I worry. After Lady Sybil,
how could I not worry?
Now, should I meet the others
off the train?
Get Mr Matthew's car
taken to the station,
and have the others brought here.
Mr Matthew can drive himself
to the hospital
and come back with the news
when he's ready.
Yes, good. Very good.
And, Anna, thank you.
Would you help to prepare her while
I make sure everything's ready?
Erm, you saved me from making
a fool of myself at the fair.
I'm afraid I'd too much to drink.
I don't know what you mean.
Well, I think you do.
And thank you.
I wish Matthew were here.
It's funny. I feel as if
I'm only half myself without him.
He'll be on the train by now,
and you won't want him in the room
till it's all over, trust me!
Oh!
It won't be long now.
We must ring Carson.
He'll be in such a state. I will.
I shouldn't have gone up north.
How could I be so stupid?
My dear,
the baby will be perfectly well.
Slightly early, but not very.
We'll just have to take
a little extra care, that's all.
(KNOCKING)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
What are you doing up here?
I just wanted to make sure there
wasn't too much harm done.
Well, there was enough harm done.
You were brave, Mr Barrow.
Very brave.
I feel badly.
I shouldn't have run off.
Oh, you should have.
Otherwise, what was I
bloody doing it for?
Were you following me?
I had to keep an eye out.
I could see
you'd had a bit to drink.
So...
..yes.
Yes, I did follow you.
Why?
You know why.
I can never give you what you want.
I understand that. I do.
And I don't ask for it.
But I'd like it
if we could be friends.
Right you are, Mr Barrow.
If that's all,
I think I could manage that.
Thank you, Jimmy.
Thank you.
Make yourself useful for
something, read the paper.
4:20 at York looks all right
for a flutter.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
We'll keep you posted.
Thank you very much indeed.
What about jelly?
That was Mrs Crawley.
It's over. Lady Mary's very tired,
but she's come through it.
They both have.
Thank the Lord!
What about the baby?
What about it?
What sex is it?
Oh! I never thought to ask.
Oh, God. Men!
Can this hot and dusty traveller
come in?
Say hello to your son and heir.
Hello, my dearest little chap.
I wonder if he has any idea
how much joy he brings with him.
Oh, my darling. How are you?
Really?
Tired, and pretty relieved.
But just think,
we've done our duty.
Downton is safe.
Papa must be dancing a jig.
I'm dancing a jig!
I feel like I swallowed
a box of fireworks.
You are going to be
such a wonderful mother.
How do you know?
Because...
Because you're such
a wonderful woman.
I hope I'm allowed to be
your Mary Crawley for all eternity
and not Edith's version,
or anyone else's for that matter.
You'll be my Mary always.
Cos mine is the true Mary.
Do you ever wonder
how happy you've made me?
You sound rather foreign.
Shouldn't you be saying, 'You'll be
up and about in no time'?
I'll do all that tomorrow.
But, right now, I want to tell you
that I fall more in love with you
every day that passes.
I'll remind you of that
next time I scratch the car.
Do.
I give you full permission.
Where are the others?
Back at the house,
panting to see you.
To see you both.
But I've sent Mother
to keep them at bay.
I wanted the chance to be alone...
..with my family.
You'd better go and tell them.
But first, I think I've earned
a decent kiss.
You certainly, certainly have.
LADY EDITH:
First Sibby, now her little cousin.
It's rather wonderful, the way
families just keep on rolling.
Did you have a good time?
I did.
Very good, in a way.
How about you?
I've been on
a bit of a learning curve.
Me too, and it isn't over yet.
These things
are always nerve-wracking.
All's well that ends well,
and it won't be long
before you'll be able to say
hello to your very own grandson.
My grandson!
Oh, my dear! How sweet
and miraculous that sounds!
Life is strange, isn't it?
In so many different ways.
No, I mean,
I think of all the uncertainty
between Matthew and Mary,
or when the money was lost,
and everything was so dark.
Yet now here we are
with two healthy heirs,
an estate in good order,
and I wonder what I've done
to deserve it?
I agree.
But then, we don't always
get our just desserts.
You'd better go down.
They'll be here in a minute.
And tell Mr Matthew
he must wait his turn.
He's seen the baby,
and they haven't.